Jimmy Lei Ba

jimmy@psi.toronto.edu

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a fourth year PhD student researching deep neural networks. In particular, my focus is on developing attention-based machine learning models in the applications of computer vision. Also, I am broadly interested in questions related to computational cognitive science, artificial intelligence and Bayesian statistics.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy, Electrical & Computer Engineering
University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario

Master of Applied Science, Electrical & Computer Engineering
University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario

Bachelor of Applied Science, Electrical & Computer Engineering
2007 - 2011

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Preprints:

• Ba, J., Kiros, J. R. and Hinton, G., (2016), "Layer Normalization", arXiv preprint arXiv:1607.06450

Publications in refereed proceedings:

University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario

- **Ba, J.**, Hinton, G., Mnih, V., Leibo, J. and Ionescu, C., (2016), "Using Fast Weight to Attend to the Recent Past", *Advances in the 2016 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'16)*
- Kraus, O., **Ba, J.** and Frey, B., (2016), "Classifying Microscopy Images Using Convolutional Multiple Instance Learning", *Bioinformatics* 32(12), 52-59
- Mansim, E., Parisotto, E., Ba, J. and Salakhutdinov, R., (2016), "Generating Images From Captions with Attention", Proceedings of the 2016 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'16)
- Parisotto, E., Ba, J. and Salakhutdinov, R., (2016), "Actor-Mimic: Deep Multitask and Transfer Reinforcement Learning", Proceedings of the 2016 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'16)
- **Ba, J.**, Grosse, R., Salakhutdinov, R. and Frey, B., (2015), "Learning Wake-Sleep Recurrent Attention Models", *Advances in the 2015 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'15)*
- **Ba, J.**, Swersky, K., Fidler, S. and Salakhutdinov, R., (2015), "Predicting Deep Zero-Shot Convolutional Neural Networks using Textual Descriptions", *Proceedings of 2015 International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV'15)*,
- Xu, K., Ba, J., Kiros, R., Cho, K., Courville, A., Salakhutdinov, R., Zemel, R. and Bengio, Y., (2015), "Show, Attend and Tell: Neural Image Caption Generation with Visual Attention", *Proceedings of 2015 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML'15)*
- **Ba, J.** and Kingma D., (2015), "Adam: A Method for Stochastic Optimization", *Proceedings of the 2015 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'15)*
- **Ba, J.,** Mnih, V. and Kavukcuoglu K., (2015), "Multiple Object Recognition with Visual Attention", *Proceedings of the 2015 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR'15)*

Jimmy Lei Ba

jimmy@psi.toronto.edu

- **Ba, J.,** Xiong and H, Frey, B., (2014), "Making Dropout Invariant to Transformations of Activation Functions and Inputs", *Advances in the 2014 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'14) deep learning workshop*
- **Ba, J.** and Caruana, R., (2014), "Do deep nets really need to be deep?", *Advances in the 2014 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'14)*
- **Ba, J.** and Frey, B., (2013), "Adaptive Dropout for Training Deep Neural Networks", *Advances in the 2013 Neural Information Processing System (NIPS'13)*

HONORS & AWARDS

Facebook Graduate Student Fellowship

2016 – Present

University of Toronto 2009 – Present

- Electrical and Computer Engineering Outstanding Student Award (2009 2011)
- University of Toronto Excellent Award in the Natural Science and Engineering (2009 2010)
- Dean's Honours List
- Collage of Physics and Engineering Science Dean's Scholarship (2007 2008)

Others

• Canadian Euclid Mathematic Competition, Special Award (2007)

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Guest lecturer on inference algorithms and message-passing, University of Toronto	2015
ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Head TA, designed two new assignments, 7 weeks of tutorial sessions, University of Toronto	2015
CSC2523 Deep Learning in Computer Vision Guest lecturer on neural programming, University of Toronto	2015
CSC321 Introduction to Neural Networks and Machine Learning Guest lectuer on probability theory and inference algorithms, University of Toronto	2014
CSC321 Introduction to Neural Networks and Machine Learning Tutorial TA, 4 weeks of tutorial sessions and lecture assistant, University of Toronto	2014
ECE1510/CSC2535 Advanced Inference Algorithms/Advanced Machine Learning Guest lecturer on deep learning, University of Toronto	2014
ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Guest lecturer on neural netowrks and deep learning, University of Toronto	2013
ECE521 Inference Algorithms and Machine Learning Tutorial TA, 6 weeks of tutorial sessions, University of Toronto	2013

Jimmy Lei Ba

jimmy@psi.toronto.edu

WORK EXPERIENCE, TEAM WORK, AND COMMUNICATION

Research Intern 2014 Google Deepmind, London, England Research Intern 2013 Microsoft Research, Redmond, Washington 2009 **Software Development Engineer** Sybase iAnywhere Inc., Waterloo, Ontario INDEPENDENT RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT 2014 - Present **Machine Learning** Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science, University of Toronto Supervisor: Geoffrey Hinton, Brendan Frey & Ruslan Salakhutdinov **Machine Learning and Computer Vision** 2011 - 2013Research Assistant, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Toronto Supervisor: Brendan Frey Signal Processing and Multimedia Wearable Computing 2010 Research Assistant, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Toronto Supervisor: Steve Mann